<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The conditions for new-planters in the territories of his Royal Highnes the Duke of York.</title>
            <author>New York (Colony). Governor (1664-1668 : Nicolls)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1665</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 3 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B09600</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing N1141</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC W23270</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">69648843</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 69648843</idno>
            <idno type="VID">185016</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B09600)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 185016)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2883:39)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The conditions for new-planters in the territories of his Royal Highnes the Duke of York.</title>
                  <author>New York (Colony). Governor (1664-1668 : Nicolls)</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([2] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by Samuel Green.</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[Cambridge, Mass.:</pubPlace>
                  <date>1665]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Signed: R. Nicolls.</note>
                  <note>Publication data suggested by Wing (2nd ed.).</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Massachusetts Historical Society Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Nicolls, Richard, 1624-1672.</term>
               <term>Land grants --  New York (State) --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Migration, Internal --  New York (State) --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>New York (State) --  Public lands --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>New York (State) --  Emigration and immigration --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>New York (N.Y.) --  History --  Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-06</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-06</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-07</date>
            <label>Pip Willcox</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-07</date>
            <label>Pip Willcox</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="conditions">
            <pb facs="tcp:185016:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>
               <hi>THE CONDITIONS FOR</hi> NEW-PLANTERS In the Territories of His <hi>ROYAL HIGHNES THE</hi> DUKE OF YORK</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>HE Purchaſes are to be made from the <hi>Indian Sachims</hi> and to be Recorded before the <hi>Governour.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Purchaſers are not to pay for their liberty of purchaſing to the <hi>Governour.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Purchaſers are to ſet out a Town, and Inhabit together.</p>
            <p>No Purchaſer ſhall at any time contract for himſelf with any <hi>Sachim,</hi> without conſent of his <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ſſociates: or ſpecial Warrant from the <hi>Governour?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Purchaſers are free from all manner of Aſſeſſments or Rates for five years after their Town-plot is ſet out, and when the five years are expired, they ſhall only be liable to th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> publick Rates, and Payments according to the Cuſtome of other Inhabitants both <hi>Engliſh</hi> and <hi>Dutch.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>All Lands thus Purchaſed, and poſſeſt ſhall remain to the Purchaſers, and their Heires, as free Lands to diſpoſe of as they pleaſe.</p>
            <p>In all Territories of his ROYAL HIGHNES, Liberty of Conſcience is allowed, Provided ſuch Liberty is not converted to Licentiouſneſs, or the diſturbance of others, in the exerciſe of the Proteſtant Religion.</p>
            <p>The ſeveral Townſhips have liberty to make their peculiar Laws, and Deciding all ſmall Cauſes within themſelves.</p>
            <p>The Lands which I intend ſhall be firſt Planted, are tho<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>e upon the Weſt ſide of <hi>Hudſon-River,</hi> at, or adjoyning to the <hi>Sopes,</hi> but if any number of men ſufficient for two or three, or more Towns, ſhall deſire to plant upon any other Lands they ſhall have all due encouragement proportionable to their Quality, and undertakings.</p>
            <p>Every Townſhip is Obliged to pay their <hi>Miniſter,</hi> according to ſuch agreement as they ſhall make with him, and no man to refuſe his Proportion, the <hi>Miniſters</hi> being elected by the Major part of the Houſeholders Inhabitants of the <hi>Town.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Every Townſhip hath the free choice of all their officers both Civil, and Military, and all men who ſhall take the Oath of Allegiance to his <hi>Majeſty,</hi> and are not Servants, or <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ay-labour<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>s<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> but are admitted to enjoy <hi>Town-lotts</hi> are eſteemed freemen of the Juriſdiction, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nd cannot forfeit the ſame without due proceſs in Law.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>R. Nicolls.</signed>
            </closer>
            <pb facs="tcp:185016:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
